Let's use descriptive statistics and visualizations to
借助描述统计学和可视化
address the question we posed with this cancer data earlier in the lesson.
我们来解决之前在课堂里针对癌症数据提出的问题
Does the size of a tumor affect its malignancy?
肿瘤大小会影响其恶性程度吗？
For this, we'd ideally compare the sizes of benign tumors with those of malignant tumors.
为此我们需要比较良性肿瘤和恶性肿瘤的大小
We can use masks to select all rows in the data frame that were diagnosed as
我们可以用掩码 (mask) 选出 DataFrame 中所有诊断为恶性的行
malignant then all rows diagnosed as benign and put them in separate data frames.
以及所有诊断为良性的行 把两者放到不同的 DataFrame 中
First, let's create a new data frame called df_m that contains only malignant tumors.
首先 我们创建一个只包含恶性肿瘤的新 DataFrame 将其命名为 df_m
Here's a breakdown of how we got this.
以下是实现这一步的具体解析
This part here, returns pandas series of booleans
这个部分返回一个 pandas 布尔值 series
indicating whether the value in the diagnosis columns is equal to M,
指出诊断 (diagnosis) 列中的值是否等于 M
and indexing the original data frame with
然后将该掩码作为原始 DataFrame 的索引
this mask will return all rows where the value in mask is true.
返回所有掩码值为真的行
In other words, where the diagnosis is
换句话说 只要是诊断为 M 的行都会被调出
M. Now that we have all the malignant tumors together in a data frame,
我们已经把所有恶性肿瘤放到一个 DataFrame 里
let's see summary statistics about the area feature which offers a good metric for size.
现在来看看 area 特征的概括性统计 这是衡量肿瘤大小的一个好指标
Let's do the same for all the benign tumors.
对所有良性肿瘤数据进行同样的操作
We can use the mean to compare these.
用平均数来比较两种数据
Although summary statistics like the mean are helpful,
虽然平均数之类的概括性统计很有帮助
it would be nice to be able to compare the distributions of
但如果可以可视化地比较恶性肿瘤和良性肿瘤的 area 特征分布
the areas of malignant and benign tumors visually.
那就更好了
Let's see a simple example of using Matplotlib to
我们来看一个简单的案例 使用 Matplotlib
create histograms for both distributions on the same plot.
将两种特征分布绘制成一个直方图
Don't worry about understanding this code right now.
别担心现在看不懂这些代码
We'll learn how to use Matplotlib in the next lesson.
下节课我们会讲授如何使用 Matplotlib
This visual suggests that there is a difference between
从可视化界面可看出
the distribution of areas for benign and malignant tumors.
良性肿瘤和恶性肿瘤的 area 分布有所不同
We don't yet have the tools to conclude that these two distributions are
我们现在还没有工具可以断定这两个分布不同
different or whether the size definitely affects the tumor's malignancy.
或断言肿瘤是否恶性与大小有关
However, we can observe from summary statistics and
但我们可以观察概括性统计和这些直方图
these histograms that malignant tumors are generally larger in size than benign tumors.
进而发现恶性肿瘤通常比良性肿瘤大